# Harry Smith

## **SOFTWARE ENGINEER | Atlanta, GA**

**PHONE** 470-654-8497 | **EMAIL** harrybsmithiv@gmail.com

**GITHUB** https://github.com/Harry-B-Smith | **LINKEDIN** https://www.linkedin.com/in/harry-b-smith/

Cloud-certified software engineer with experience in web development and enterprise web application development. Extensive knowledge of Java, relational databases, RESTful APIs, modern frameworks for building microservices, version control, JavaScript/TypeScript, CI/CD, TDD, automated testing, Spring, Node.js, Express.js, PostgreSQL, AWS, Azure, and Google Cloud Platform (GCP). Proven track record of learning new applications quickly.

LANGUAGES	FRAMEWORKS/ LIBRARIES	DATABASES	TOOLS
• Java	• Spring Boot	• PostgreSQL	• GCP
• JavaScript/TypeScript	• Angular	• MySQL	• Docker
• Git	• React	• Oracle SQL	• Kubernetes

### **WORK EXPERIENCE**

Software Engineer, Newbold Advisors (The Home Depot), Atlanta, GA (remote), August 2023 - January 2024

- Modernized legacy apps using Java/Spring Boot and cloud tech, resulting in a highly-rated app for nationwide use
- Enhanced REST API efficiency by 15%, resulting in faster frontend responses through codebase optimization
- Streamlined the process of Docker image creation and deployment to GCP/Kubernetes using GitHub Actions and Spinnaker, improving CI/CD efficiency
- Developed JUnit and Mockito unit tests for new features, boosting code coverage and application reliability
- Participated in Agile/Scrum practices, including daily stand-ups, sprint planning, and retrospectives

#### Java Consultant, FDM Group, New York (remote), December 2022 – July 2023

- Engineered a responsive calendar feature using Angular, HTML, CSS, JavaScript/TypeScript, enabling users to view weekly schedules through a user-centric design
- Assumed the role of backup tech lead, leading team to 10% reduction in merge conflicts and a 15% increase in deployment efficiency
- Led bug fixes and codebase enhancements, resulting in a 15% increase in code coverage and a 10% reduction in bug rates
- Facilitated meetings to foster team communication and collaboration among frontend, backend, and business analysts, increasing team productivity
- Collaborated with designers and the performance team on feature updates, improving user experience and adherence to web content accessibility guidelines

### Web Developer, self-employed, Atlanta, GA, February 2016 - December 2022

- Contributed to the design and development of responsive, user-friendly sites using HTML, CSS, Bootstrap, WordPress, Shopify
- Acquired hands-on experience with Node.js and Express.js for server-side application development
- Collaborated with teams of developers on various projects, gaining experience in version control using Git

- Constructed a single-page web application (SPA) ecommerce websites from scratch, enhancing brand image
- Designed and implemented a database for quick data retrieval

### **SKILLS**

Java, relational databases, RESTful APIs, modern frameworks for building microservices, version control, JavaScript/TypeScript, CI/CD, TDD, automated testing, Spring, Node.js, Express.js, PostgreSQL, AWS, Azure, and Google Cloud Platform (GCP)

#### **EDUCATION**

Savannah College of Art and Design, Bachelor in Digital Media

### **CERTIFICATIONS & TRAINING**

Microsoft Azure Cloud Fundamentals, AZ-900 Certified

**FDM Group**, Software Development Program: Java — 2023

- SQL (queries, joins, databases)
- Unix (functions, parameters, writing shell scripts, loops)
- Java Core Fundamentals and Key Tools (Mockito, Maven, Eclipse, Git, Version Control Systems)
- JUnit (Unit Testing), TDD, UML, Object-Oriented Principles, Data Structures and Algorithms
- Data Access (using JDBC, JPA)
- Web Development (HTML, CSS, JavaScript, XML)
- Spring Framework (Core, Boot, Data, Web MVC)
- Spring Rest (Rest Clients, APIs, Web Services)
- Angular (TypeScript, Services, Forms)
- Agile Project Management (Agile/Scrum)

Per Scholas, Software Engineering: Full Stack Java Developer Program — 2022